My Grill Me skills and Grill with Docs
have been out there for a while now, and
people all around the world are using
them as a replacement for plan mode in
agents. However, I sometimes hear from
people using them, like Codex just ask
me 200 questions, this issue here. And I
kind of wince a little bit. The idea of
these skills is that they relentlessly
question you, is that they continually
ask you questions until you reach a
shared understanding about something.
And what that does is it relies on the
skill of the person answering the
questions. The person answering the
questions, in other words, you using the
Grill Me skill, need to be good at
planning. You need to understand things
like scope. You need to have a sense of
what questions require what level of
fidelity to answer. And this is why I
want to make this video. I want to make
you really good at using these skills,
because these skills themselves are
really not super long, and they're
designed to aid you as an engineer, not
replace you as an engineer. So, I've got
a list of nine things that people get
wrong with these skills. But before we
do that, we're going to look at a few
lenses for how to understand those
failure modes, because if we don't
understand them in the correct way,
we're not going to be able to change
them. Now, if you like the way I teach
and you like the thing I'm teaching
about, then you are going to really
enjoy my AI coding for real engineers
cohort, which the next one starts on
June 1st. It has only 1 day and 11 hours
left for 30% off. So, definitely
you want to get on that. Hopefully, I
can post this video today, so you have
time to actually purchase it. So, let's
get started. The first thing to consider
here is that when we go into a grilling
session, what we're really trying to do
is answer questions. There are probably
some things that we don't know about the
thing that we're going to build. Now,
these questions come at different levels
of fidelity that are required to answer.
I'm taking this language from Ryan
Singer's amazing book Shape Up. High
fidelity questions are questions where
you need a really zoomed in, really
detailed, high fidelity image in order
to understand it. And that might mean,
for instance, how will this piece of UI
feel when we're using it? Should we
split all of these form fields into
multiple different pages, or should we
have one enormous form where we fill
them in? The only real way you're going
to get kind of understanding of that is
a high-fidelity prototype, or actually
building the whole thing. Whereas,
low-fidelity questions are questions
that you don't need a high-fidelity kind
of prototype or image to answer. Things
like, what should what URL should this
route live on, or things like that. You
really just need to answer the question.
And the first failure mode I see with
the Grill Me skills is trying to answer
high-fidelity questions during a
grilling session. In other words, there
are questions that are grillable, in
other words, answerable in a grilling
session, and questions that are
ungrillable, questions that are not
answerable in a grilling session. So,
then, what do you do when you encounter
an ungrillable question? When the
question is about feel, when you need to
actually see something higher fidelity
in order to answer it. Well, the thing I
tend to do is I tend to have a
prototyping handoff. So, let's imagine
that in my first session here in the
blue, I've done some grilling, and I
reach an ungrillable question, a
question that I need to see in a higher
fidelity. What I do is I use the handoff
skill, which I will link to below, to
handoff to a prototyping session, where
I will then spend another session kind
of just prototyping on that question,
seeing it in a higher fidelity. And
then, whatever I learn from that, I will
handoff back to the original grilling
session, so that I can continue with the
grillable questions. So, that's what a
lot of my sessions look like, where you
have a grill with docs, you then handoff
to a prototype session, and you handoff
back to the original grill with doc
session. That's how I answer those more
higher fidelity questions. The next
concept we need to understand here is
scope, how large a thing you are
grilling. If the thing you're grilling
is too big, then you're going to end up
hitting two problems. First of all, if
the scope is too large, then you're
probably going to have high fidelity
questions that are kind of hidden in
there that is quite hard to answer
without actually seeing the full thing.
It's always easier to build off of
something that you know works and that
you've done a good job on rather than
trying to endlessly plan scope out into
the future. This is what a lot of people
hit when they try to schedule, you know,
days and days of tasks for their work on
is that they end up with crap because
they aren't building on a foundation
that they are aligned with. In other
words, they've tried to sort of push out
too far into the future without building
on something solid. There's also a
practical constraints here. If you end
up grilling on too larger thing, you're
going to end up hitting the dumb zone of
the model. Sure, you might start your
grilling session with a, you know,
nearly empty context window, but as you
keep going and going and going, okay,
you've hardly got to the thing that
you're, you know, not even answer half
the questions yet and we're still
hitting the dumb zone up here, at which
point you might need to hand off or
compact or do something a little bit
awkward, all of which could have been
avoided if you just picked a smaller
scope to start with and then you'll be
able to comfortably grill within the
smart zone. For those who don't know,
about 120k is where I estimate most
state-of-the-art models, that's where
their dumb zone begins. And so you've
got to keep a really keen eye on your
context window in order to make sure you
don't push past that because the model
will start getting too strained kind of
in its attention relationships and start
making stupider decisions. What this
basically means is if you start out with
a large scope like this, which is
probably too big for the agent to
handle, instead it might be better to
ahead of time ask the agent to break
down this scope into smaller scopes,
which you can then grill on individually
and answer all of those questions. The
next lens I want you to look at here is
whether you're being passive or whether
you're being active with the agent and
specifically in your grilling sessions.
Many of these huge grilling sessions
that I see people having, I worry that
they're being too passive with the
agent. When I'm doing grilling, I'm
always quite active, always trying to
lead the conversation. And remember,
it's a conversation, not an interview.
The agent is asking you these questions,
but you know, it is your job to figure
out where you're going and figure out
the scope and keep things on track. And
so, if you're being too passive, then
it's very easy for the agent to just do
stupid things with the interview, like
ask you 540 questions, explode the
scope, ask questions about stuff that
are way too low fidelity. You have to
take an active hand. But it's also
possible to be too active, to just keep
grilling on something that is just too
low fidelity when you need to actually
build something to see the thing in
action. And so, there are two failure
modes hidden here, being too passive, in
other words, sitting back too much, and
actually being a bit too pigheaded, and
not getting to code fast enough. So,
it's important to consider when you're
using these skills where you fall on
this axis, whether you're too passive or
whether you're actually just a bit too
pushy and active. Another failure mode
here is that people don't value the
thing that they're creating during the
grilling session, which is that when
you're answering these questions, when
you're growing this context window with
really valuable, you know, answers that
you've given, design decisions that
you've taken, this little blue bit of
context window here is incredibly
valuable. Now, usually your goal here is
that if you've got enough budget left,
then you can immediately start going
ahead and implementing. In other words,
you plan for a little while and then you
go, "Okay, let's just implement this. We
don't need to hand off. We've got enough
space left in the context window to just
implement it based on the design
decisions I've already taken." However,
if you're already at the point where you
need to, you know, quit out of this, you
need to basically hand off, then it's
probably time to make a PRD. My two PRD
skill is a nice way of creating a
handoff document that's kind of more
tailored to engineering, which can be
useful on a multi-session or just a
single session. But one crazy thing I've
seen people getting wrong is they
actually clear the context first, and
they create a new context window, and
just run two PRD in there. This is
totally crazy to me. What are you doing?
You've created this incredible session
here where you've got this, you know,
100,000 tokens of really good design
decisions, and you're just going to
chuck it away? Every grilling session,
every decision that you make in that
session is so valuable. You know, that
should be recorded somewhere, and either
turned into code or put into like a
handoff document that you can kind of
refer to later. It is really important
that you don't just chuck away the stuff
inside the grilling session. I think
probably this is a just a skill issue.
People need to be a lot more aware of
context management, about kind of the
decisions they're making in terms of
clearing, compacting, handing off. So
yeah, that was a crazy one for me. Make
sure you preserve the decisions that
you've made in your grilling session,
and create some kind of handoff artifact
about them. Another thing people get
wrong is that they use too dumb a model
for grilling. Understanding which
questions are low fidelity,
understanding which questions are high
fidelity, figuring out what the right
questions to ask to prompt you to make a
stronger design, that is something you
need a good model for. If we think about
where models draw their knowledge from,
there are kind of two sources. The first
one is their contextual knowledge, the
stuff that you have passed them
specifically in their context. This
might be from reading files or from user
prompts or from research they do by, you
know, calling tools and bringing the
tool results back. But there's also
their parametric knowledge, the things
that they were trained to see and
understand. This is much less reliable,
but it is kind of what we're relying on
here. We're relying on the model's
innate understanding of systems and
applications to prompt us with good
ideas of things we might not have
considered yet. Because if we had
considered them, then we'd have passed
them in as contextual knowledge, but
we're relying on its kind of innate
understanding in order to provide us
with off-the-wall suggestions, strange
ideas. Now, when you're relying on
parametric knowledge like this, you need
a model with lots of parameters, and
that is usually what the big frontier
models have. And not only that, but
they're also, you know, top-of-the-line
trained. They are also just more capable
than smaller models. And so, using too
dumb a model is a really common failing
mode I see during grilling because we're
so reliant on parametric knowledge. What
most people don't know is you can
actually use a kind of dumber model for
implementation because most of the
information you're passing there is
contextual. You know, by the time you
get to implementation, you've usually
got a detailed implementation plan.
You're passing in the relevant files in
the codebase, so it's got some things to
copy. You know, not a lot of that is
parametric. It's mostly contextual.
Finally, and this is a dead simple one,
but so many people don't do this. You
should grill multiple sessions in
parallel. Usually, the way it works is
I'm grilling one session, and then I,
you know, type something to it, or
usually I'm dictating to it. I answer
its question, and then I go over into
the other other session that's usually
finished by that point. I answer its
question, and then I go back to the
original session. And I just bounce
around like this. People say this is,
you know, context switching, but really
it's just managing two separate Slack
threads at the same time. You know, it's
really not that hard. And sure, you're
making a lot of high-level decisions
here, but this is really the only way I
found of increasing throughput and
getting more planning done in less time.
Usually, I max out at two sessions here
unless one of them is doing a
particularly long-running task like some
research, in which case I will try three
uh if I'm feeling spicy and feeling high
energy, but mostly two is my limit. But
either way, I'm doubling my throughput,
and it feels pretty nice to do, and you
should definitely be doing this if you
have the mental capacity for it. I also
think that grilling is something that
you do get better at, and as you get
better at it, you can add more
throughput and more parallelism. So,
let's summarize all the things we
learned. We learned that grilling is
primarily about questions. We have
low-fidelity questions and high-fidelity
questions. Low-fidelity can be answered
just by a question and answer. In other
words, it's a grillable question. But,
high-fidelity ones are ungrillable. You
may need to go into a prototype mode by
using handoff to handoff to a
prototyping session to just figure out
that question or maybe that question and
a bunch of others and then go back to
the original grilling to continue.
Figuring out the correct scope of the
work is essential. If you try to grill
too much, then you will end up just kind
of blowing through your contacts window,
burning your own stamina, and you won't
have anything to show for it. If you're
too passive in your grilling sessions,
then you're just going to sit there
while the computer just says, you know,
bombards you with more and more
questions. But, if you're too active,
then you might end up just grilling
endlessly on low-fidelity questions when
what you really need is just to get to
code. You need a smart model so that you
can rely on its parametric information
to give you better suggestions and give
you better questions to answer. And
finally, I would recommend grilling two
sessions at once. Once you've mastered
these basics and you understand what
each session is doing, you should be
able to flip between them really nicely.
And probably, you could even go up to
four if you have a more plastic brain
than I do. Overall, thanks for watching,
pals. And if you enjoyed this, then
you'll really enjoy my AI coding cohort
for real engineers, which is whoa, 1 day
10 hours left to get it at a discount.
You get a bunch of video content and
interactive exercises organized in a way
for maximum speed and maximum efficiency
of learning. You get me to answer your
questions in office hours and in the
Discord chat. You know, it's great. By
the way, if you dug this video, my
YouTube is exploding recently, so thank
you all for that. I massively appreciate
it. I really enjoy making these videos.
I'm loving making the skills. I think
we're up to we just beat Gary Tan's G
stack in terms of number of stars, which
is wild to me. And if you have an idea
for a video you want me to make next,
then let me know about it cuz I thrive
off your suggestions and your ideas. So,
thanks for watching, and I will see you
very soon.